<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>java | Academic</title>
    <link>/tag/java/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/java/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>java</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 15:47:45 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>java</title>
      <link>/tag/java/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Face Recognition App</title>
      <link>/project/facerecognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 15:47:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/facerecognition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Android app performs face recognition and identification through the smartphone&amp;rsquo;s camera. The app uses an internal database containing the known identities, including sample photos. The app allows the user to check the database content, delete or add new identities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Face Detection is powered by Haar Cascade Classifier. Face Feature are extracted by VGG2 trained on VGGFace2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Classification is performed by weighted kNN on the extracted face features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data processing is powered by OpenCV for Java.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WanRaptor</title>
      <link>/project/wanraptor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 15:47:08 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/wanraptor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WanRaptor is my first job as a Software Engineer and Project Manager with a big enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WanRaptor is an embedded system used to validate an application in a lab environment by emulating bandwidth limitations, latency, packets loss and jitter commonly found in WANs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project involved the development from the ground up of the full-stack Graphical User Interface, including management of hardware resources, installation, secure licensing and user interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WanRaptor is widely used in many laboratories all over United States and further.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lockstep Library</title>
      <link>/project/lockstep-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 15:46:57 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/lockstep-library/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This library was developed as group project for Concurrent and Distributed Systems course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea behind this project was to implement first-hand a synchronization layer like most multiplayer games use nowadays. The simulation (game) in object is collaborative effort where multiple clients generate inputs that drive it. The synchronization layer has to guarantee that each client processes inputs in the correct order so that everyone has a consistent view of the simulation, without ever sharing its state directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We chose to implement the most strict version of lockstep, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow for the simulation to go on speculatively in case of delays, contrary to most games. We also chose the client-server structure, which should give the lowest delay in most cases. In order to make the library as generic as possible, we chose to use Java Serialization for marshalling/unmarshalling. This gives a huge overhead in terms of bandwidth, and should be reconsidered given the specific application needs.&lt;/p&gt;





  
  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-client-structure&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/project/lockstep-library/featured_hudad196ad72a610935122c69fb1f6c933_37697_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Client Structure&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/project/lockstep-library/featured_hudad196ad72a610935122c69fb1f6c933_37697_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;811&#34; height=&#34;561&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Client Structure
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  
  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-server-structure&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/project/lockstep-library/server_hu65cca0095768a98fecaf5ac0150b7e6f_44481_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Server Structure&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/project/lockstep-library/server_hu65cca0095768a98fecaf5ac0150b7e6f_44481_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;1001&#34; height=&#34;402&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Server Structure
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
